# Nguyen Thi Chi Lam

**BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT ANALYST** 



**Date of birth** 15/10/2001

**Gender** Female

Address
District 5, Ho Chi Minh City

**Phone** 0967423249

Email

nguyenlam151001@gmail.com

Website

linkedin.com/in/lâm-nguyễn-a42b31286

# **Objective**

Applying for the role of Business Development Analyst at Rize will allow me to use my knowledge of market research, data analytics, and climate finance. Having a background in finance, technology, and economics, I am dedicated to fostering effective rice value chains, increasing market expansion, and creating sustainable company models.

## **Skills**

- Market Research & Business Strategy
- Data Collection & Analysis
- Stakeholder Engagement & Communication
- Project Management

#### **X** Tool & Technologies:

- Microsoft Excel, Power BI, Google Sheets
- PowerPoint, Google Slides
- Python, SQL
- JIra, Trello

### **Activities**

June 2020 - Sep 2020

Manga Trans & Edit Team

Volunteer Translator

May 2020 - Jun 2020

#### **UIT SAFE Volunteer**

Participate in the volunteer movement to measure the temperature of students, lecturers and visitors to UIT during the Covid19 outbreak.

Dec 2019

#### **UIT ENGLISH SPEAKING CONTEST**

Participate in the English contest about the era of technological development.

# **Experience**

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

#### **CJ OLIVENETWORKS VINA**

Business Analyst & QA Tester Intern

#### **Business Analyst:**

- ◆ Analyzed As-is business processes and proposed To-be process improvements.
- ◆ Designed contract management screen mockups, ensuring an user-friendly interface.
- Defined business requirements and documented workflows using Jira/Confluence for project tracking.

#### **OA Tester:**

- Developed detailed test cases and conducted functional testing before deployment.
- Performed scenario-based testing to ensure system reliability.
- Reported and tracked software defects using Jira, collaborating closely with developers to improve product quality.

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

#### Freelance Pet Broker (Cat Trading Consultant)

- Acted as an intermediary between cat owners and buyers, negotiating fair deals.
- Researched market trends to match potential buyers with suitable cat breeds.
- Advised customers on pet selection and basic care.
- ◆ Closed multiple transactions and earned commissionbased revenue.

## **Education**

Oct 2019 - Nov 2024

#### **UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - UIT**

Major: Information System

# **Certifications**

TOEIC Certificate (Score 835) | 2024